# **JOSEPH WRIGHT**

07740 199135

joe@joejag.com

code.joejag.com

I help people deliver software that's well designed, fully tested and released early.

During 2011 I become an independent contractor specialising in the financial domain. With Barclays Wealth I created SOA applications with an innovative distributed database design helped by the Scrum methodology. During this contract I trained people to adopt TDD and piloted a change to using BDD within the testing group to improve collaboration.

Recently I joined a startup to help them get their first product out to market, taking advantage of the cloud technologies that are enabling companies to rapidly release software.

Before contracting, I joined JPMorgan Chase to assist their investment bank using XP agile practices to drive business more effectively and efficiently. In May 2010 I was selected to join their elite Expert Engineer program to focus on difficult problems seen within the bank.

I blog at code.joejag.com and have started offering one to one mentoring on TDD and OOD after success running Code Retreats. I'm known for speaking at conferences about techniques such as Continuous Delivery and engaging in "deliberate practice" which organisations and developers can use to improve their skills and delivery.

#### Specialties

Clean code, Continuous Delivery, mentoring, technical speaking, Java, Ruby, BDD, Linux administration and agile techniques.

**EXPERIENCE** 

Oct 2012-Present Emerge Adapt

### **Software Developer (Contract)**

Working with cloud software specialists on their beta adaptive case management product with the tyre and insolvency industries.

Using Amazon Web Services to scale out a Rails based Ember.js application. I work closely with customers to hear their problems and work on features for the product in an iterative fashion.

To allow frequent safe delivery there is an understandable strong focus on testing. While using Cucumber for BDD, I also worked with the creator of RSpec to create well tested features.

May 2011-Sep 2012 Barclays Wealth

## **Senior Developer (Contract)**

Developed an SOA application to provide client data to other consumer and provider systems backed by a distributed cache. This project reduced the cost of integration while improved the availability of client data.

Used Continuous Delivery practices to automate the release process of a vendor system allowing the whole group to perform releases in minutes rather than days.

Worked closely with the testing team to allow them to adopt practices such as version control and CI. Created a pull system for deployment to empower the team.

Provided advice and training on agile retrospectives, deployment automation and BDD.

2006-2011 JPMorgan Chase

#### **Technical Lead/Architect**

Senior developer with build, plan and delivery responsibilities.

Drove a firm wide initiative for improving code quality and developer tooling. This led to improved testing practices and reduced licence costs across the firm.

Developed applications for traders to mark up price correlations with Eclipse RCP and web services, resulting in decreased risk for commodities trading.

Drove adoption of XP based agile practices like CI, TDD and Pair programming across different lines of business.

Worked at Sun, Commercial Microbiology Ltd and Scottish Qualifications Authority from 2003 to 2006

EDUCATION

2010 SEI - Software Architecture Professional Certification

Carnegie Mellon University

2004-2005 (Commendation) Msc eCommerce

University of Aberdeen

2000-2004 2:1 Bsc (Hons) Computing Science

University of Aberdeen

SKILLS

Languages: Java, Ruby, Clojure, Javascript Libraries: Ember, Spring, Rails, Eclipse RCP Databases: Coherence, Sybase, MySQL, MongoDb